ford.co.za 2016-12-01

# Ford South Africa

### **Privacy Policy**

**1\. General Statement:**

* * *

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. This privacy statement explains our policies and practices regarding online customer information. It is through this disclosure that we intend to provide you with a level of comfort and confidence in how we collect, use, and safeguard personal and other information we collect or that you provide through this website, and how you can contact us if you have any questions or concerns. It is our sincere hope that by explaining our data handling practices we will develop a trusting and long-lasting relationship with you. By using the site, you agree to the terms of this privacy statement. 

**2\. Information About Our Organization and Website and General Data Collection Practices:**

* * *

This Privacy Statement applies to ford.co.za. ford.co.za is administered by a third-party vendor on behalf of Ford Motor Company, Simon Vermooten Road, Silverton, Pretoria] 

The business purpose of this website is to provide visitors: (1) with knowledge of the features and benefits of the complete line of cars, crossovers, SUVs and trucks; (2) with purchasing-related information such as available incentives; and (3) with service information. 

For added convenience, a select set of site features are accessible from web-enabled mobile devices as a mobile-optimized web experience.  These site features may be limited in functionality. 

**3\. Personally Identifiable Information We Collect From You:**

* * *

When you visit ford.co.za we will not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you provide it to us voluntarily. For purposes of this Privacy Statement, personally identifiable information is information that identifies you as an individual such as your name, street address, telephone number, and email address. If you opt not to provide us with personally identifiable information you can still access our website, however you will be unable to request a quote or test drive from a dealer, or receive a brochure or marketing communications including emails. 

Our primary goal in collecting personally identifiable information from you when you visit ford.co.za is to provide you the functionality and services that you need to have a meaningful and customized experience while using the site features. 

See Section 12 regarding links to third-party sites, including widgets.

**4\. How We Use the Personally Identifiable Information We Collect:**

* * *

_Personally identifiable information_ collected on ford.co.za may be used to: 

  * Fulfill a site user request (e.g., brochure fulfillment, marketing or promotional materials including emails)
  * Respond to your comments or requests for information
  * Meet a request for or to develop new products or services
  * Make the user experience more customer friendly
  * Develop new and improved products, services and marketing
  * Contact you if necessary in the course of processing or shipping an order for products or services
  * Generate site analytics that improve our site layout, content, product offerings and services
  * Compile user data that is stored in our corporate database and may be used for marketing and other purposes
  * Match personal data collected here with data about you that we collect through other sources
  * Comply with legal requirements 

**5\. Other (Non-Personally Identifiable) Information We Collect From Site Visitors:**

* * *

ford.co.za collects other “non-personally identifiable information” from site visitors. This means that we do not track these items on an individual basis that identifies the site visitor, but rather gather and collect this information on an aggregate [or anonymous] basis that includes all site visitors. Non-personally identifiable information includes tracking the site pages that are visited or the amount of time spent on our site. 

If you visit this site using a mobile device, we collect additional non-personally identifiable information which may include the type/model of the mobile device viewing the site and the mobile device’s service provider and operating system. 

Our primary goal in collecting non-personally identifiable information from you is to be able to perform site metrics that allow us to improve the functionality of the website.

We may use session and persistent “cookies,” session logs, spotlight ads/web beacons/GIF/pixel tags, banner ads or links, and third-party click tracking analytics tools (such as Adobe) to collect aggregate or other non-personally identifiable information about site visitors. An explanation on collection methods and how they work is included in Section 7 - Methods to Collect Information, below.

**6\. How We Use the Aggregate or Non-Personally Identifiable Information We Collect:**

* * *

Non-Personally identifiable information collected on ford.co.za may be used to: 

  * Compile aggregate and statistical data to help in website design and to identify popular features
  * Measure site activity to allow us to update our site to better meet user wants and needs
  * Provide you content that may be of interest to you based on pages visited and items viewed
  * Make the user experience more customer friendly
  * Develop new and improved products, services and marketing

ford.co.za utilizes non-personally identifiable information for the purpose of performing analytics on the user’s experience while visiting this site. This analysis: 

  * Is performed on an aggregate level and does not identify you or your information personally
  * May involve the use of a third-party vendor acting on behalf of ford.co.za
  * Is performed in order to improve our website and the user experience
  * May include the use of session and/or persistent cookies to track user movement across this and other Ford 
Motor Company websites or to track other events within or across this and other Ford Motor Company websites 

**7\. Methods to Collect Information:**

* * *

A “cookie” is a small text file that helps us in many ways to make your visit to our website more enjoyable and meaningful to you. For example, cookies avoid you having to log in every time you come back to one of our websites. They also allow us to tailor a website or advertisement to better match your interests and preferences. There are a couple different types of cookies.

A “session” cookie is stored only in your computer’s working memory (RAM) and only lasts for your browsing session. When you close all your browser’s windows, or when you shut down your computer, the session cookie disappears forever. 

A “persistent” cookie is stored on your computer’s hard drive until a specified date, which could be tomorrow, next week, or 10 years from now. Persistent cookies stay on your computer until either a) they expire, b) they are overwritten with newer cookies, or c) you manually remove them. Most browsers can be configured not to accept cookies, however, this may prevent you from having access to some site functions or features.

This site may use third-party click tracking analytics tools (such as Adobe) to capture clickthrough statistics.

ford.co.za may use spotlight ads/web beacons/GIF/pixel tags which are site instrumentation tools that help us to determine, for instance, whether a page has been viewed or not and, if so, how many times. Emails or electronic newsletters we send may use tools (e.g., pixel tags or web beacons) to gather email metrics and information to improve the reader’s experience such as how many of the emails are opened, if they were printed or forwarded, the type of device (e.g., mobile or PC) from which they were opened, and the city, state, and county associated with the applicable IP address. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a webpage, including an ad banner, can act as a web beacon.

This website may generate a “session log” when you visit our site. We use session logs to help us determine how people travel through our site. In this way, we can structure our pages so that the information most frequently visited is easier to find. By tracking page visits, we can also determine if the information we’re providing is being used. The only data gathered is the Internet Protocol (IP) address from which you came, the website that referred you, the pages you visited and the date and time of those visits.

Users may be directed to ford.co.za via banner ads or site links. Ads or site links that are placed by ford.co.za use cookies or web beacons to deliver metrics on the effectiveness of the ads or links. They do not collect personally identifiable information from the user.

**8\. Sharing Your Information:**

* * *

ford.co.za does not share, sell, or rent personally identifiable information with independent companies for their own use without providing you a choice.

Personally identifiable information that you provide to us in the course of requesting a product or service through this website may be gathered and stored in one or more of our corporate databases and be used for purposes of contacting you for things like promotional offers, marketing programs, or other communications from this website or other Ford Motor Company programs and services.

We may share personally identifiable information that we collect about you with other companies within the Ford Motor Company family of companies or subsidiaries. Our “family of companies” is the group of companies related to us by common control or ownership. We share information within this “family” as a normal part of conducting business and offering products and services to our customers.

Personally identifiable information that you provide to ford.co.za may be shared with our authorized dealers. This is necessary, such as, in order to honor your request for a price quote on a vehicle or in order to provide a dealer with information for purposes of contacting you in their regular course of business. The dealer is not restricted by ford.co.za in their use of your data.

We may share PII with vendors, contractors or partners in the normal course of business. Vendors, contractors or partners of ford.co.za who have access to your personally identifiable information in connection with providing services for ford.co.za are required to keep the information confidential and are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for ford.co.za.

Site metrics for ford.co.za may be shared with other Ford Motor Company websites or subsidiaries or affiliates.

ford.co.za will disclose your personally identifiable information, without notice, if (1) in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Ford Motor Company, its affiliates or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Ford Motor Company, its affiliates or this site; or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Ford Motor Company or affiliate personnel, users of their websites, or the public; or (2) if required to do so by law.

Environmental Grant, contest or sweepstakes entrants only: If you are providing personally identifiable information in connection with a contest or sweepstakes through this website, and if you are selected as a winner, we may include your personally identifiable information in a publicly available winner’s list. See the applicable contest or sweepstakes rules.

**9\. Access To and Control Over the Use of Your Information:**

* * *

To correct or update your personally identifiable information contact us at:

Mailing Address  
Simon Vermooten Rd  
Silverton   
Pretoria  
Telephone: 0860 011 022  
Ford Customer Relations: fordcrc2@ford.com   

so that we may be able to process your changes. ford.co.za will use reasonable efforts to correct any factual inaccuracies in your information.

The scope of access available for this request is for information stored in the database that holds the data for ford.co.za. Any personally identifiable information that has been collected from you on other Company websites will not be accessible or changeable through the processing of this request.

**10\. Security of Your Information:**

* * *

Safeguarding information of visitors to our website is important to us. While no systems, applications or websites are 100% secure, we use systems, policies and procedures to maintain accuracy of information and to protect information from loss, misuse or alteration.

When you send personally identifiable information, such as email address or telephone numbers, to ford.co.za we use technologies such as “Secure Socket Layers” (SSL) or “Transport Layer Security (TLS) to protect your data. SSL and TLS are encryption technologies that helps safeguard your personally identifiable information against misuse by unauthorized individuals.

Vendors, contractors or partners of ford.co.za who have access to your personally identifiable information in connection with providing services for ford.co.za are required to keep the information confidential.

Vendors are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for ford.co.za.

**11\. Processing of Personal Data:**

* * *

By visiting this site and by providing your personally identifiable information to us, you understand and consent to the collection, use, processing, transfer, and disclosure of your personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information globally --- including to the United States – in accordance with this Privacy Statement. Therefore, by visiting this site and by providing such information, you consent to the transfer of such information across country borders, and to the use, processing, and disclosure of such information in global locations. Your consent shall be deemed to include your consent to transfer of the personally identifiable or non-personally identifiable information to locations that may have different levels of privacy protection than in your own country.

**12\. Links to Other Sites:**

* * *

ford.co.za provides links to other websites. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of all sites that you visit, including those whose links are provided so that you can understand how those sites collect, use and share your information. ford.co.za is not responsible for the privacy statements, content or data handling practices on other websites. 

If you use the Google Map functionality this website, you agree to be bound by Google’s [Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/intl/en_us/help/terms_maps.html) and [Google's Privacy Policy.](https://www.google.com/intl/en_us/help/terms_maps.html) In addition, if you are on a mobile device and the GPS feature on the mobile device is turned on (if it has such capability). GPS data may be utilized by the mapping service to determine your location in order to fulfill your request for location services.

If you choose to utilize the AddThis widget to share content on this website with your friends, please note that AddThis is an independent third party and is not a vendor, contractor or partner of ford.co.za. All information (personally identifiable or aggregate) that is collected by the AddThis widget is collected by AddThis and is subject to the AddThis Privacy Policy and not the ford.co.za Privacy Statement. 

**13\. Children’s Privacy:**

* * *

ford.co.za does not knowingly intend to collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. 

If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information a parent or guardian of that child may contact us at the address, phone number or email address listed in section 14 if they want this information deleted from our records. We will then make reasonable efforts to delete the child’s information from the database that stores information for ford.co.za. 

**14\. Contacting Us:**

* * *

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about this online privacy statement for ford.co.za, ford.co.za privacy practices, or have any questions regarding the contents of this website please contact us at

Simon Vermooten Rd  
Waltloo  
Pretoria  
Telephone: 0860 011 022  
Ford Customer Relations: fordcrc2@ford.com 

ford.co.za is committed to working with consumers to obtain a fair and rapid resolution of any complaints or disputes about privacy and the handling of your data. ford.co.za will be happy to respond to your questions and comments. 

**15\. Privacy Statement Effective Date and Revision Days:**

* * *

Occasionally we may update the privacy statement for ford.co.za in order to reflect any changes to the website or our privacy practices. If we update this statement, the new statement will be posted to the website ten (10) days prior to the changes taking effect.

The information contained in this website is an overview intended for awareness purposes only. Visuals may show specifications, accessories and options not available in South Africa. Left-hand drive models may be shown for illustrations purposes only. 

All information, specifications and illustrations are based on the latest product information available at the time of publication. FMCSA reserves the right to make changes at any time, without notice, to the colours, material, equipment, specifications and models, and is not responsible for typographical errors. Such changes may affect vehicle pricing and vehicle content. All prices shown are recommended retail prices, which are not binding on FMCSA or the Dealer network. The recommended retail price includes VAT and Environment Tax (Environment Tax includes CO2 Emission Tax and Tyre Tax) but excludes Dealer delivery and related charges. 

The declared fuel consumption and CO2 emission figures were achieved during technical laboratory testing in accordance with the legislated technical specifications (SANS 20101: 2006 / ECE R101: 2005). Fuel consumption and CO2 emissions figures are used to compare different vehicle types under uniform conditions and are not necessarily indicative of real-life driving conditions. Note that the actual fuel consumption and emissions levels will depend on many factors including individual driving habits, prevailing conditions and vehicle equipment, condition and use. 

Please contact your nearest approved Dealer or the Customer Relations Centre to confirm specific features, applicable terms and the non-binding retail prices of vehicles recommended by FMCSA in effect at the time of purchase.
